<xml>
	<news>
		<new>
			<titlenews>About</titlenews>
			<descnews>With so many seafood choices, how do we determine which are best for our health, the environment and local communities? While most seafood guides focus primarily on environmental sustainability, Food and Water Watch’s Smart Seafood Guide also considers human health implications and the socio-economic impact of consuming various types of seafood.
                
Food and Water Watch’s Seafood Guide comes from a review of over 100 types of wild, farmed and invasive species, which we have evaluated according to three major categories:
                
Human health considerations
                
Environmental considerations
                
Socio-economic considerations
                
Below are the five major criteria we evaluate for the seafood we recommend in our guide. We encourage you to consider these criteria before making a seafood selection at a grocery store, market or restaurant. </descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
		<new>
			<titlenews>Contaminants</titlenews>
			<descnews>Is the species associated with contaminants like PCB or mercury?
                
Does the species come in contact with parasites or diseases?
    
Has the type of seafood been frequently associated with chemical contamination?
    
Do warnings exist advising consumers to limit consumption?

Food and Water Watch’s seafood guide does not recommend any type of seafood that research indicates cannot safely be consumed by adults four times per month due to mercury or PCB contamination, nor does it recommend seafood that is likely to be contaminated with chemical residues or toxins.
            </descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
		<new>
			<titlenews>Status of the Stock</titlenews>
			<descnews>Is the species overfished or experiencing overfishing?
                
Is it well-managed (is there an effective management plan in place limiting catch, promoting long-term health, etc.)?
    
    
Is it likely to be overfished do to long life cycles and slow growth rates, or is it more resilient through fast maturation and high rates of reproduction?
    
    
Food and Water Watch’s seafood guide does not recommend species that are overfished, undergoing overfishing or that we evaluate to be at risk due to a combined lack of management and biological susceptibility.</descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
		<new>
			<titlenews>Catch / Farming Method</titlenews>
			<descnews>What types of gear are used to catch the species and does the gear cause any habitat damage or bycatch (e.g. are other species of marine life unintentionally killed during its use)?
                
If the species is produced in a farm facility, what are the ecological impacts?
    
Are there user conflicts involved in farming the species (does the farm promote responsible energy and water usage, efficient feed conversion, and proper disposal of effluent, while avoiding the use of chemicals and/or drugs)?
    
Is the farm susceptible to escapes that could jeopardize wildlife?
    
Does the farm contribute to the spread of disease/parasites?

Food and Water Watch’s seafood guide does not recommend wild fish from fisheries that neither use nor are working to use capture methods with minimal habitat damage. It also does not recommend fish from fisheries with high rates of bycatch. For farmed fish, it does not recommend types from farms with significant environmental impacts.</descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
        <new>
			<titlenews>Eco/Socio/Cultural Significance</titlenews>
			<descnews>Is this a key species for a community (does the community predominantly fish for this species and depend on it)?
                
Is the species revered or sacred to a community?
    
What are the impacts of a fishery or fish farming industry on local communities?
    
To date, Food and Water Watch’s seafood guide is the only guide to consider these socio-economic implications. It gives preference to types of seafood that support local, domestic economies. </descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
        <new>
			<titlenews>Key Species</titlenews>
			<descnews>Is the species important or necessary for the survival of other wildlife (is it is a primary food source or does it create critical habitat for other wildlife)?
            
Our seafood guide does not recommend seafood, of which a high rate of human consumption would threaten the needs of other species.</descnews>
			<linknews>1</linknews>
		</new>
	</news>
</xml>
