<xml>
	<news>
		<new>
			<titlenews>Organic</titlenews>
			<descnews>“Organic”, “sustainable,” “eco-friendly” — what do they all mean? Seafood labels can be very confusing. For example, the Marine Stewardship Council (MSC) says its label certifies that seafood is sustainably managed.  Unfortunately, many of the fisheries it approved are actually associated with significant environmental problems. Organic labels, if you see them, don’t mean a thing here in the United States for seafood — there are not yet U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) organic standards for seafood. Rather than relying on labels, the best method for you as a consumer is to ask questions and learn directly from the people who are selling the seafood. </descnews>
			<linknews></linknews>
		</new>
        <new>
			<titlenews>COOL</titlenews>
			<descnews>Country-of-origin labeling (COOL) is important, but existing laws fall short of requiring all information to be provided for all fish products. In 2005, the USDA developed mandatory COOL rules, which were intended to help inform consumers about where seafood comes from and if it is farm-raised or wild-caught. Unfortunately, USDA did not create a strong labeling program.
                
“Processed” seafood is exempt, leaving more than 50 percent of fish products sold in the United States without labels. Processed seafood can be anything that has been altered in a substantial way, such as cooked, smoked or canned seafood, or that has been mixed with other ingredients. Examples include seafood soups, seafood medleys, fish blocks and breaded or salted seafood. Excluding processed seafood from COOL requirements is especially troubling, because this category of seafood product has a high risk of contamination.
                
Ninety percent of fish sellers, such as wholesale markets, don’t have to label the origin.
                
No enforcement mechanism exists and violators face minimal fines. </descnews>
			<linknews></linknews>
		</new>
        <new>
			<titlenews>Mercury</titlenews>
			<descnews>Mercury and PCB contaminant information for the 2012 Smart Seafood Guide is drawn from Environmental Defense Fund’s (EDF) Health Alert List. EDF calculates health advisories based on government databases and scientific studies and establishes recommended safe consumption levels for men, women and children. Food and Water Watch does not include any species in our guide that cannot be safely consumed by adults four times per month.</descnews>
			<linknews></linknews>
		</new>
        <new>
			<titlenews>Dirty Dozen</titlenews>
			<descnews>The species on our “Dirty Dozen” list fail to meet two or more of our criteria for safer and more sustainable seafood. For instance, imported coastal farmed shrimp, which is the worst offender on our list, is associated with potential contamination, environmentally problematic farming methods and negative socioeconomic implications for coastal communities in the United States and abroad. Open-water farmed salmon is also associated with concerns in each of these categories. Bluefin tuna, a wild-caught specie, raises major red flags in two areas: the status of the stock is very low due to international unsustainable catch methods/overfishing and the fish associated with high levels of mercury contamination.
            </descnews>
			<linknews></linknews>
		</new>
	</news>
</xml>